Shumetie A. Tefera Sr. MULESOFT DEVELOPER

Phone No: +1 213-290-4212 Address: 6114 Brynhurst Ave Los Angeles,

E-mail: alemu.s.tefera27@gmail.com CA 90043, USA
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/salemutefera527 Website: sss-ssss-alive.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An engineering enthusiast, self – motivated and Certified MuleSoft developer with 7+ years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing application integration solutions using Mule ESB, MQ Series, ETL/BI tools, and object-oriented programming Java. Experienced in developing Mule ESB flows and integrations by using service-oriented architecture (SOA) in Mule Runtimes. Designing and developing Mule ESB projects using various connectors like HTTP, Database, Transformers, FTP, FILE, SFTP, IMAP, VM, JDBC, Sales force, and Web Service Consumer as part of Integration and DataWeave for integrating various applications, which are on-premises and hosted on cloud using synchronous and asynchronous Mule flows. Profound Experience in using ActiveMQ, AWS suite for Asynchronous message queuing for guaranteed delivery pattern. Experience working with Agile Methodologies and SCRUM. Effective team player and high adaptability to new technologies. Worked on developing batch integrations to transfer data in bulk between enterprise applications using MuleSoft Enterprise Service Bus. Experienced in building complex Mule Flows, Scopes, Error Handling strategies, Message Filters, Validation, Transformation, Message Enricher, and Flow Controls. Expertise in Database Design, normalization, writing SQL queries & PL/SQL Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Sequences, Indexes and Views etc. Good exposure to CI/CD tools like Jenkins, GitHub, Mayen, MMC, and Anypoint Runtime Manager. Good experience in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Requirement Analysis, Design, Development, and Testing applications. Experienced in deploying Mule flows and securing the APIs using the platform in Mule Cloud hub. Demonstrated a growth mind-set and willingness to learn through collaboration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Anypoint Platform:** ESB, Anypoint API Designer, MMC, Cloud Hub, Runtime Manager, Anypoint Studio, RAML, Anypoint Design center, Anypoint Management center, Anypoint Exchange, Runtime engine & services, API-led connectivity, Anypoint Security
- **Anypoint Studio:** Instant run of Mule application inside a local runtime, Visual editors to configure API specification files, Integration with Exchange to import templates, Embedded unit testing framework, Built-in support to deploy to CloudHub
- **Connectors:** Anypoint MQ Connector, Kafka Connector, LDAP Connector, CloudHub Connector, Microsoft Dynamics CRM Connector, Salesforce Connector, ServiceNow Connector, HTTP, Database, Workday, File, FTP/SFTP, AMQP, Microsoft Service Bus
- **Messages & Message Transformation:** JSON, XML, Data Weave, Java Collections, Data Mapper, JMS connector, Active MQ, Anypoint MQ, RabbitMQ
- **Database:** MS SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, PosgreSQL, Mongo DB, NoSQL, Dynamo DB, JDBC, ETL, ELT
- **Cloud Platform**: **Azure** (Azure VMs, Cosmos DB, Azure SQL, Azure Data Lake Gen2, Blob storage, Kubernetes, SQL pools, Synapse analytics, Stream analytics/
 - **AWS** (EC2 instances, Amazon SQS, SNS, S3, AWS Glue, Amazon EKS, RDS, Amazon Dynamo DB- NoSQL, VPC, Route 53, Direct connect, Cloud front, API Gateway, storage Gateway, Kinesis, Docker)
- Unit Testing: MUnit, Postman, ARC (Advanced Rest Client), SOAP UI, data weave preview, mocking services. Jira
- **Languages & Web Technologies**: Java, C#, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React js, Node js, HTTP, REST, XML, JSON, WordPress, Shopify, squarespace
- **CI / CD:** Maven, Jenkins, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Artifactory
- **Source Control:** TFS, Git, Azure DevOps, and Jira
- Security Tools and Services: OATH2, JWT, Open ID, Service Principal, Managed Identity, IAM
- Tools/ IDE: Anypoint Studio, Eclipse, MS SQL Server, Visual Studio, Visual Studio code, Power BI

- **Communication tools**: Teams, Slack, Zoom, GoToMeeting, and Google Hangouts.
- **Operating Systems:** Window 7/8/10, Linux (Ubuntu)

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

- MuleSoft-Certified Developer
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect-Associate
- Certified in SQL Server Database Development & Administration, MS BI
- Certified in Full Stack Web Development (MERN)
- MSc. from Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia
- BSc. from Mekelle University, Ethiopia

WORK EXPERIENCE

McKesson Corporation - Chino, CA

Jul 2020-Current

Sr. MuleSoft Developer

Responsibilities:

- Developed RAML documents using Anypoint Design Center, published them to Anypoint Exchange and Implemented the APIs using API-Kit Router in Anypoint Studio, tested using ARC and used API Gateway as a proxy service.
- Created Flows, Sub Flows, Exception strategy and DataWeave transformation in Mule configuration.
- Used Mule Batch processing to handle the large data and used the batch processing capabilities of DataWeave to transform large payloads.
- Worked on Mule flow variables, record variables, various connectors like File, FILE, SFTP, IMAP, HTTP, Oracle database, Salesforce.
- Worked with Message Filters, Message Translators, Content enricher, Scatter-gather and Mule Transaction Integration patterns.
- Develop API Portals to document the APIs.
- Used CI / CD tools like Jenkins, Maven, and GitHub during the development and deployment
- Participated in requirements gathering sessions with application developers and functional users
- Implemented and consumed SOAP Web Services using WSDL Files and tested using SOAP UI for Mule ESB flows and Deployed Mule applications onto Cloud Hub.
- Implemented asynchronous messaging using Active MQ and AWS suite and involved in design, built, and deployed applications utilizing AWS stack (including Amazon EC2, S3 and SQS).
- Implemented Devops best practices of CI/CD for Mule applications using Maven, AWS Docker.
- Used Basic and OAuth Authentication mechanisms to consume REST API's.
- Used DataWeave's different flavors (like map. mapObject, reduce, plunk, flatten, filter) extensively to do data transformations along with custom Java Classes.
- Implemented Integration flows using Mule Anypoint Studio to connect to REST Services, Databases, and ActiveMQ broker.
- Implemented JMS to communicate with other applications in deciding further processing.
- Utilized CloudHub connector in the mule flows for triggered alerts during exceptions and to capture the failed records for further recovery.
- worked with the Business & other application teams in designing robust and scalable integration solutions to meet system needs using MuleSoft Integration Suite

Optum Medical Group, Lawndale, CA MuleSoft Developer

Sep 2019 – Jun 2020

Responsibilities:

- Designed and developed enterprise services using RAML and REST based APIs, used Postman for testing.
- Developed Mule flows to integrate Data from various sources into Database, from ActiveMQ topics and did some transformations at the integration layer.
- Developed Mule flows using different Mule connectors like Salesforce, AMQP, AWS and Azure connectors, FTP, SFTP, JMS.
- Implemented and consumed SOAP web services and tested using SOAP UI for Mule ESB flows.

- Used different transformers, exception handling, testing & Security of MuleSoft ESB endpoint through OAuth.
- Integrated Mule ESB system by utilizing Active MQ, Http, File system and SFTP transports.
- Extensively used mule components that include JDBC Connector and Transaction Manager.
- Have written MUnit test cases to validate the Mule flows and done with asynchronous messaging using Active MQ.
- Used GIT and Devops as a version and source controlling tool and deployed the application On Premise as well as on CloudHub.
- Actively participated in daily meetings and reviews.
- Experience in Developing graphical user interface by using JSP, HTML, and CSS and Implemented user input validations using JavaScript and jQuery.
- Created JDBC applications to access and query a database and Manage Transactions in JDBC.
- Wrote SQL Statements for retrieving and updating data with varied complexity and used JDBC Connections and WebSphere Connection pool for database access.
- Wrote complex SQL scripts (Queries, stored procedures, triggers) and prepared power BI dashboards to view different decision-making reports for senior management.
- Used AMQP Endpoints to connect to RabbitMQ which is a messaging queue and used Salesforce and SAP connectors.
- Utilized CloudHub connector in the mule flows for triggered alerts during exceptions and to capture the failed records for further recovery.
- Generated Use case diagrams, Activity flow diagrams, Class diagrams and Object diagrams in the design phase.
- Developed MuleSoft's solutions that allow data to flow seamlessly, whether on-premises or in the cloud, by supporting healthcare information standards such as HL7 and MLLP
- Deployed Mule applications using different deployment models including CloudHub, hybrid, RTF, PCE.

City National Bank of New Jersey— Newark, NJ IIB Developer/API Developer Responsibilities:

Feb 2018 -Aug 2019

- Participated in the development of SOA platform which migrated the existing legacy applications in to ESB layer comprising of Message Broker/IIB and MQ Series.
- Problem determination using local error logs and by running user traces and service traces.
- Configured the broker runtime in DEV, SIT, QA and PROD environments.
- Ensured clear understanding of business requirements and timely deliverables.
- Handled Message Transformation between XML, COBOL Copybook and C Structures.
- Participated in Low-level design of message flows and message models. Coding in ESQL to implement the routing rules and transformation rules for mapping the messages.
- Responsible for developing technical design documents for various Interfaces based on functional designs and API
- Created new message flows and message models using applications and library concepts of IIB.
- Created transformation logic using ESQL, Java and developed error handling message flow using Java Compute and Compute nodes.
- Created RESTFUL web services using HTTP Nodes to extract member information for a group from backend database and send it to service requestor in JSON format.
- Designed and developed Web services (SOAP and Restful) in Message Broker.
- Used ESQL and Java Compute Nodes to extract / load data from databases.
- Worked with cross-domain application teams to identify the goals and provided solution.

Alpha Works Technologies, LLC – Fresno, CA MSSQL/ETL/ BI Developer

Jul 2016 - Dec 2017

Responsibilities:

- Created, and managed primary objects such as database, tables, views, stored procedures, triggers, database links, indexes, and privileges.
- Developed SSIS packages to Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) data into the data warehouse from relational database- SQL Server 2012/2014, MS Excel, and Flat files.
- Created and maintained dataflow diagrams for ETL processes
- Created parametrized queries, generated tabular reports, sub reports, drilldown reports, using Expressions
- Involved in performance monitoring, tunning, and capacity planning.
- Designed, deployed, and maintained complex reports using SQL server and SSRS
- Prepared Visio diagrams/documents to track and implement the blueprint of the ETL dataflow/process implementation from Initial phase, Ongoing, Deployment to Production Environment.
- Created packages with different control flow options and data flow transformations such as Conditional Split, Multicast, Union all and Derived Column etc.
- Supported the migration of data from Heterogeneous Sources and different formats to relational data warehouses, staging databases using complex Stored Procedures, SSIS packages as well as command prompt scripts.
- Connected data sources by Business Intelligence tools (SSIS/power BI), linked database objects and inline queries
- To persist and transfer data between pages Session State, View State, Cookies and Query Strings were used.
- Participate in development of artifacts such as Use Case Models, Use Cases, and Activity Diagrams/Workflow Models.
- Wrote conversion scripts using SQL, stored procedures, functions and packages to migrate data from SQL server database to Oracle database.